A Guide to the Papers of B.F.D. Runk, 1935-1976
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of B.F.D. Runk 1935-1976
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6852-ao and 6852-ap
This collection consists of ca. 5200 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The collections were archival transfers made by Professor Runk, "The Union," Troy, Virginia on 19 May and 11 June 1976, respectively.
Scope and Content Information
These additions (#6852-ao and ap) to the papers of B.F.O. Runk comprise ca. 5200 items spanning the years 1935-1976. The materials vary considerably in content and encompass a wide range of concerns. The three majoy categories are: Runk's general correspondence; items relating to his role as student and teacher at the University of Virginia; and materials relevant to his services as a trustee of the Miller School of Albemarle County.
Included within the general correspondence file are personal notes from friends and acquaintances, invitations to various formal and informal university functions, letters of recommendation for students, notes of congratulation to Runk for various services performed and awards received during his later years at the University. In addition to the general correspondence, there are also speeches made by him to university organizations and others beyond the confines of the university and papers related to his membership in various professional organizations.
Much of the Runk material is concerned with his academic specialty, biology. For the period beginning 1935 there are his student notes for various biology courses he took, lecture and laboratory notes from his days as a biology professor, and reports issued by Runk (or made available to him) on projects undertaken in conjunction with the Biology Department. In addition, there are the results of various weather reading projects, and several studies undertaken by him in non-university related capacities (for example, his pollen study of Nantucket Island, and his Piney River, Virginia study).
Runk served for several years as a trustee of the Miller School of Albemarle County, and his papers provide a fairly complete record of that institution for the years 1968-1975. They also detail Runk's personal and financial contributions to the Miller School. As a trustee, Runk was privy to virtually all documents emanating from the school, many of which are available here.
Organization
The collections, which have been interfiled, arrived at the library in rough topical order and have been arranged chronologically within particular rubrics. The general correspondence file is followed by correspondence and papers on specific topics in the following order: Runk's papers as a student, his papers as a professor of Biology at the University of Virginia, special biological projects such as the Piney River Project, his work with University of Virginia organizations, his membership in various professional organizations, the Miller School of Albemarle County, Hollymead, and a miscellaneous section.
Contents List
- Correspondence and Papers of B.F.D. Runk 1940-1970, 13 folders (Box 1)
- Correspondence and Papers of B.F.D. Runk 1971-1974, 5 folders (Box 2)
- Correspondence and Papers of B.F.D. Runk 1975-1976 April (Box 3)
- Correspondence of B.F.D. Runk n.d. (Box 3)
- B.F.D. Runk's student work: Comparative Anatomy, Notes, Drawings, Exams ca. 1935 (Box 3)
- B.F.D. Runk's student work: Comparative Anatomy Drawings ca. 1936 (Box 3)
- B.F.D. Runk's student work: Biology Lab Notes and Instructions n.d. (Box 3)
- B.F.D. Runk's student work: Miscellaneous Biology Notes ca. 1935-1936 (Box 3)
- B.F.D. Runk's student work: Embryology Notes ca. 1935 (Box 3)
- B.F.D. Runk's student work: Embryology Drawings and Papers ca. 1935 (Box 3)
- B.F.D. Runk's student work: Exams 1935, 1936, 1949 (Box 4)
- B.F.D. Runk's student work: Term Papers ca. 1935 (Box 4)
- B.F.D. Runk's student work: Notes and Papers re Vertebrates ca. 1935 (Box 4)
- B.F.D. Runk's student work: Zoology Lab Guides 1936 (Box 4)
- Biology 1: Lab Materials ca. 1950-1954; 1957-1958, 2 folders (Box 4)
- Biology 1: Synopsis of lectures 1957-1958 (Box 4)
- Biology Examinations 1962 May; 1966 August (Box 4)
- Report of Self Study Committee of U. Va. Biology Department 1974 Jan. (Box 4)
- Correspondence and copy of M.A. Thesis of M. D. Phillips 1974-1975 (Box 4)
- Lab Experiments in Plant Physiology n.d. (Box 5)
- Biology 133: Laboratory Exercises n.d. (Box 5)
- Songs and Poems re Biology n.d. (Box 5)
- Engineering Report re: Property of the Blandy Experimental Farm, University of Virginia, Boyle, Virginia 1962 (Box 5)
- Correspondence, Papers and Notes re: Blandy Farm Experimental Station 1969-1971 (Box 5)
- Nantucket Island Pollen Surveys, includes Correpondence between B.F.D. Runk and W. Ripley Nelson 1952 Oct. - 1955 Feb. (Box 5)
- Civic League of Nantucket 1952 Survey re: Poison Ivy and Ragweed 1952 Dec. (Box 5)
- Correspondence re: Piney River Project 1952 Aug. - 1953 Dec. (Box 5)
- Piney River Biological Projet: Monthly Progress Report 1953 April-1955 May (Box 5)
- Correspondence re: Piney River Project 1954 (Box 5)
- Report of Piney River Biological Project 1954 March (Box 6)
- Correspondence re: Piney River Project 1955 Jan.-June (Box 6)
- Biological Survey of the Piney River, Virginia Area and Evaluation of the effects of water borne wastes 1955 (Box 6)
- John B. Lewis' catalogue of plants collected in Seward Forest and nearby territory 1940-1949 (Box 6)
- Reptiles and Amphibia of Seward Forest ca. 1940-1944 (Box 6)
- John B. Lewis' catalog of plants collected in Seward Forest and adjoining territory 1940-1943 (Box 6)
- B.F.D. Runk: Timber Contract 1966 April (Box 6)
- Weather Readings of "The Union," Fluvanna County 1972 Dec.-1975 Dec. (Box 6)
- B.F.D. Runk's Correspondence and Papers re: Fraternities 1947 Dec.-1948 Feb. (Box 6)
- Omicrom Delta Kappa: Nominations 1968 Nov.-1969 April (Box 6)
- Graduation Exercises: Documents relating to 1968-1970 (Box 6)
- Deliberations and Report of Committee on Scholarship Funding 1968 Sept.-1970 May (Box 6)
- Founder's Day Exercises: Documents relating to 1970-1971 (Box 7)
- Speech Files, includes Documents, Clippings, Notes for Speeches and Addresses by Runk 1959-1965, 3 folders (Box 7)
- Speech Files 1966-1968 (Box 7)
- Notes for speeches n.d. (Box 7)
- Speech Files includes Documents, Clippings, Notes and Speeches by B.F.D. Runk n.d. (Box 8)
- The Nantucket Maria Mitchell Association Annual Reports 1962-1974, 2 folders (Box 8)
- B.F.D. Runk: Virginia Academy of Science - Natural Resources Committee 1964 March-1968 Sept. (Box 8)
- B.F.D. Runk: Virginia Resource-Use Educational Council 1967 Sept. (Box 8)
- The Miller School: Correspondence and Papers 1964-1968, 5 folders (Box 9)
- The Miller School: Correspondence, Special Committee to select a superintendent 1968 Jan.-Aug. (Box 9)
- The Miller School: Correspondence re vita of Robert J. Lawton 1968 Feb.-Aug. (Box 9)
- The Miller School: Correspondence and Papers 1969 (Box 9)
- The Miller School: 1970-1975, Correspondence and Papers (Box 10)
- The Miller School: Advisory Committee Minutes 1967 Feb.-1969 Feb. (Box 10)
- The Miller School: Budget Statements 1963-1969 (Box 10)
- The Miller School: Official Information 1967-1968 (Box 10)
- B.F.D. Runk: The Miller School Quarterly Reports 1964 May- Dec. (Box 10)
- The Miller School: Printed Matter (catalogues) n.d. (Box 10)
- The Miller School: Printed matter (handbooks, promotional literature, Samuel Miller's Will, articles and the school) n.d. (Box 11)
- The Miller School: Miscellaneous Materials n.d. (Box 11)
- Bills, Hollymead 1931-1938 (Box 11)
- Bills, Correspondence re Hollymead additions 1940 (Box 11)
- Bills, Hollymead 1951-1957, 2 folders (Box 11)
- B.F.D. Runk: Miscellaneous (pictures, citations, pamphlets, poems, etc.) n.d. (Box 11)
- Miscellany includes tribute to Ivey F. Lewis, birthday card for Runk and two mock certificates 1954 April & n.d. (Box 11)